Chezre Fredericks Curriculum Vitae

MY VISION

Make my contribution to society, securing a South Africa we can all enjoy.

EXECUTIVE SUMMARY

Good day, I am a motivated and driven professional seeking to broaden my experience as a business leader.

I am an excellent choice because:

I am in the process of **completing my MBA at the University of Stellenbosch Business School** (USB). On completion of this degree I will be equipped with advanced and flexible management skills. By leveraging USB's focus on leadership, strategic thinking and the stewardship of society, I will be prepared for the volatile, uncertain, complex, ambiguous world we live in.

I am problem solver with analytical skills. All industries, all sectors and all organisations face problems completing their core activities. The skills I have learnt through the MBA program have given me the problem-solving ability needed to address these issues. Whether it be the softer skills needed to manage high-performing teams or the numerical skills needed to leverage the mass amounts of data organisations have today. I am ready to resolve the problems of today and tomorrow.

I chase down my dreams. The last three years have been transformative as I have pursued my post-grad studies. Finishing my first post-grad degree last year has given me the motivation to set bigger goals for my life. While completing my MBA is a big goal to achieve, I believe that there are bigger dreams to chase down, for example, a career in entrepreneurship.

Thank you in for your time.

PERSONAL DETAILS

13 Alberta Street, Punts Estate, 7945 Cell: 083 679 2774

Email: <u>chezrefredericks@gmail.com</u>

Sex: Male

DOB: 12 September 1982

Marital Status: Married

ID Number: 8209125079086 Nationality: South African

Languages: English and Afrikaans

Driver's License: Code 08 Health: Good Criminal Record: None

PROFESSIONAL SKILLS

- Systems Analysis
- Requirements Elicitation
- System implementation
- Process Modelling
- Software Development
- Software Support

PERSONALITY SKILLS

- Excellent problem-solving ability
- Innovative and creative
- Great communication skills
- Natural leadership ability
- Resilient and handles pressure well
- A team player with multitasking ability

QUALIFICATIONS

- Bachelor of Commerce Degree in Information Systems (UWC)
- Bachelor of Commerce Honours in information systems (UCT)
- Masters in Business Administration (in progress -University of Stellenbosch Business School)

TECHNICAL SKILLS

- Sage ERP
- Kerridge ERP
- Salesforce CRM
- CiviCRM
- MsSQL & MySQL DBMS
- .NET, PHP, javascript, CSS
- SOA (incl handling JSON, XML through API)

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Position: Operations

Company: Penny Pinchers t/a The Tile House

Period: 2004 to 2005

Scope of Work Done:

- Relief Cashier
- Warehouse operations including stock receiving, stock counting, picking and packing, processing delivery notes
- Maintaining the stock file, including pricing and procurement from locally based vendors

IT desktop support

Position: Junior Business and Systems Analyst

Company: Penny Pinchers Support Office

Period: 2006 - 2008

Scope of Work Done:

- User training training users on Penny pinchers business processes with Kerridge ERP.
- Development of new business processes.
- System & Process Implementation, this included migrating users from legacy systems to Kerridge ERP.
- Maintenance and production of User training documentation.
- Report writing.
- Development KPI dashboards.

Position: Web Developer

Company: Customer Care Solutions

Period: 2008 - 2009

Scope of Work Done:

- Web Development for micro web applications.
- .NET development for the in-house call centre software.
- Database Administration.

Position: Systems Analyst/Programmer Company: The Bible Society of South Africa

Period: 2009 – present day

Scope of Work Done:

- Migration of legacy accounting system to Sage ERP.
- Migration of donor database from legacy system to CiviCRM (a donor/contact relationship management system).
- Web Development for the Bible Society's enterprise system with integrations to external systems:
 - Donor CRM (CiviCRM)
 - o Bulk mailing with Mailchimp
 - Bulk SMS with grapevine
 - Bank statement processing through scheduled CSV file imports
 - Sage300 ERP
- Integration between Sage ERP and external systems like Skynamo CRM and Bookmaster ERP.

REFERENCES

- Joos Maree (Head of IT Bible Society of South Africa) 083 258 7934
- Bruce Cowling (Senior Systems Analyst Kerridge ERP) 083 474 1611
- Robert Burgoyne (Managing Director Sim Direct) 082 474 4184